<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on R for the rest of us</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on R for the rest of us</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A bit of a hack</title>
      <link>/2017/12/02/a-bit-of-a-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/02/a-bit-of-a-hack/</guid>
      <description>This week I also finished up a feature of an application that I have been thinking about implementing. I wanted to summarize data entry by site location. The problem is that variable I am trying to summarize is free data entry&amp;ndash;hence many ways to write the name of the school and mispelling. I used a bit of hack with the gsub function.
My approach was this.
site$school &amp;lt;- toupper(site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;DOWDELL MIDDLE&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DOWDELL&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;DOWDELL MAGNET&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DOWDELL&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;DOWDELL SCHOOL&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DOWDELL&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;DOWDELLMIDDLE&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DOWDELL&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;DOWDELL MIDDLE&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DOWDELL&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;BLAKE ACADMY&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;BLAKE ACADEMY&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;BLAKEACADMY&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;BLAKE ACADEMY&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;BLAKE ACAMAY&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;BLAKE ACADEMY&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;DREAM ACADENY&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DREAM ACADEMY&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;FREEDOM MS&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;FREEDOM MIDDLE SCHOOL&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;RIBUALT MDDLE&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;RIBAULT MIDDLE&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school)  However, my sense is that there is a better way implment this with regular expressions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Entry Application</title>
      <link>/2017/12/01/data-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/01/data-management/</guid>
      <description>My intent was to build a data entry application with Python using the flask web environment. Somehow I managed to talk myself into using Shiny with the help of this post from Dean Atalli. It only took me about a couple of distracted hours with 3 kids to get through the tutorial and a morning to update a line of code to get the example working.
The pros to this approach are the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>working directory</title>
      <link>/2017/11/04/working-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/04/working-directory/</guid>
      <description>This seems basic in retrospect but one of the biggest challenges starting with R was understanding the concept of the working directory. For the most part, I figured the working directory out. However a bad habit that festered was changing the working directory in the chunks of my Rmd files.
Below is how I would configure my R chunks to read data or source scripts/functions. My data sits in multiple folders in the Project Folder, and I could not get the chunk to read the data or source scripts without setting the working directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviewing Functions</title>
      <link>/2017/10/14/reviewing-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/14/reviewing-functions/</guid>
      <description>I am starting on the new year of project and was revisiting some functions. I had a function that created a csv file of duplicate values for every organization that submitted data. The function was useful but a pain to run the function for every organization on separate chunks.
I figured there had to be better way. The following is an incremental improvement to the old process but I do have a sense there is a better way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging</title>
      <link>/2017/09/02/debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/02/debugging/</guid>
      <description> An approach to debugging Take the approach that most likely it is your fault that something is not working. You are simply not providing clear enough directions to the computer&amp;ndash;Your computer is simple and has no grit to problem solve your sloppiness.
Be thankful that that the computer is throwing an error rather giving a result that is wrong.
My approach to debugging accounts for the following:
 Data Types Spaces Syntax Errors and missing commas Updated package/library Other silly mistakes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonprofits and Data Management</title>
      <link>/2017/06/11/nonprofits-and-data-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/11/nonprofits-and-data-management/</guid>
      <description>Do you agree that good infrastructure makes your life easier? Have you thought about the infrastructure of managing your program data? What are your systems that are in place to collect, manage and analyze your data?
My experience is that nonprofit organizations do not manage their program data in an optimal way and often manage their data in ways that make it challenging for employees to do their work. My gravest concern is that many nonprofit managers may not even recognize there is a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogdown lessons</title>
      <link>/2017/05/20/blogdown-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/20/blogdown-lessons/</guid>
      <description>One big challenge in rendering the site was using the R studio GUI Git. How many times did I restart my computer before I deduced the problem? The Git process would stall out.
To solve, I used the new Git desktop feature (https://desktop.github.com/) and it worked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>makefiles and automation</title>
      <link>/2016/10/20/makefiles-and-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/20/makefiles-and-automation/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on trying to automate my workflow and want to learn to utilzie a makefile system to run a status report. To be honest, I am struggling to understand what I am reading from the tutorials.
Next step will be to clone the repository and work through the examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>