<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Craftsmanship on R for the rest of us</title>
    <link>/categories/craftsmanship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Craftsmanship on R for the rest of us</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/craftsmanship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduled Time</title>
      <link>/2017/10/14/scheduled-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/14/scheduled-time/</guid>
      <description>More on the book Deep Work. Cal Newport suggest scheduling every minute of your day.
This is challenging&amp;ndash;it takes training and practice but it has had profound impact on my productivity and well being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converging to Deep Work</title>
      <link>/2017/09/04/converging-to-deep-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/04/converging-to-deep-work/</guid>
      <description>I finished reading Deep Work by Cal Newport last month. Mr. Newport puts a framework and rules to what I think we already suspect. The book made me think of two other books Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maitenance and The War of Art. Both of these books put an emphasis on the benefits of craftmanship.
The concept of taking a break from focus rather than distraction is profound and his challenge to quit social media for 30 days benefical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craftsmanship</title>
      <link>/2017/06/03/craftsmanship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/03/craftsmanship/</guid>
      <description>I have been thinking a lot about craftsmanship and trying to improve my work habits. I listened to a podcast that featured Vince Vaugn, and I was impressed with Vaughn&amp;rsquo;s story. Vaughn&amp;rsquo;s commitment to the craft of acting came through in the episode. In most cases, we rarely think about the process or the journey people take on their road to success. One aspect that stuck out what his commitment to the process and working to get better at acting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>