<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R for the rest of us</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on R for the rest of us</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Freeing Educational Data With A Shiny App</title>
      <link>/2018/04/04/freeing-educational-data-with-a-shiny-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/04/freeing-educational-data-with-a-shiny-app/</guid>
      <description>I built a Shiny Application to free data from a spreadsheet on the Florida Department of Education website. I learned a lot&amp;ndash;specifically making the input variable reactive, sprinkling in html to make it look how I want, and using the DT package for useful rendering of the data.
Reactive I knew that I wanted to split the data into school types&amp;ndash;elementary, middle, and high and had a sense that my input value would need to be reactive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Balance</title>
      <link>/2018/03/05/automaton-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/05/automaton-balance/</guid>
      <description>I listened to this podcast with the GLG president&amp;ndash;Alexander Saint-Amand and Kara Swisher.
In this podcast, they discuss the future of education. My takeaway from the discussion is that value is found between the balance of automating and the wisdom of humans. The controversy around YouTube and advertisements on Infowars seems to be another case in point where turning your self completely to automation seems risky.
Another, interesting discussion centered around the dynamic between teacher and students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing the Branch</title>
      <link>/2018/03/05/embracing-the-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/05/embracing-the-branch/</guid>
      <description>I read this interesting post from Suzan Baert about getting started with Git/Github. I think recommendation 2 about using a dummy repo to experiment with is key and I would recommend this approach to my younger self. My biggest issue was not having the reps and confidence.
One branch at a time I have been using Git for about three or four years and just in the last month started using branches to make changes on a consistent basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Driving The Readxl package</title>
      <link>/2018/02/26/test-driving-readxl-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/26/test-driving-readxl-package/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: I am interested in school attendance data and found an interesting data set on the Florida Department of Education Website. This seemed like a good opportunity to learn the readxl package. This post closely follows with the examples on the Github Repo.
The file consists of a count of students who were absent more than 21 days in the 2015-2016 school year. The data is broken down by school district and school; the data also includes enrollment data and percent of students who missed more than 21 days by school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Streak</title>
      <link>/2018/02/26/the-streak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/26/the-streak/</guid>
      <description>I was not able to get a post published this weekend. It was written but I could not get to render on the site. This post is way to check things out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Driving readxl</title>
      <link>/2018/02/23/test-driving/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/23/test-driving/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I am interested in school attendance data and found an interesting data set on the Florida Department of Education Website. This seemed like a good time to learn the r readxl package in order to wrangle spreadsheets in the wild. This post closely follows closely with theexamples on the Github Repo.
The file consists of data from a survey of schools in Florida that provides a count of students who were absent more than 21 days in the school year 2015-2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I started with R</title>
      <link>/2018/02/18/how-i-started-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/18/how-i-started-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I was reading a thread on the R-Studio Community about how to convince colleagues to switch from Excel to R. It made me think about what prompted me to make the switch. I am not sure there is anything worse than analyzing survey data in Excel.
In July of 2011 I started a job at a nonprofit organization as a Quality Assurance Coordinator. My main duty was to develop surveys that measured customer satisfaction and program quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My week in R</title>
      <link>/2018/02/17/my-week-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/17/my-week-in-r/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny Fun</title>
      <link>/2018/02/17/shiny-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/17/shiny-fun/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>get_dupes function--Janitor Package</title>
      <link>/2018/02/10/janitor-for-dupes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/10/janitor-for-dupes/</guid>
      <description>The Janitor Package was recommended to me on the R4DS Slack Channel. I was finally able to check it out this weekend and the get_dupes function is what I have been looking for my whole R life. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to play with some of the tably features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under the hood with geom_bar</title>
      <link>/2018/02/01/r4ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/01/r4ds/</guid>
      <description>I have struggled with bar plots using ggplot2&amp;ndash; I never bothered to look under the hood to understand what was happening; I just hacked away until I get a reasonable looking bar plot.
This has changed since I signed up for the R4DS community slack group in December and have been working my way slowly through the R for Data Science Book. As, I have been going through Chapter 3, I finally started looking under the hood and learning the fundamentals of gglot2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>list.files</title>
      <link>/2018/01/27/list-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/27/list-files/</guid>
      <description>I learned how to use the list.file function from Dean Attali&amp;rsquo;s Post: Mimicking a Google Form with a Shiny App
However the power of the list.file function finally set this in this week. The function is not merely a method to list the files&amp;ndash;it can be a method to put all those files to an object that can be manipulated&amp;ndash;mind blown. 😄
Here is my script to combine multiple pdf files using the tabulizer package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Shiny</title>
      <link>/2018/01/19/shiny-for-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/19/shiny-for-teaching/</guid>
      <description>It was a struggle for me to learn to write my own functions in R. The moment it did sink in; My though was this&amp;ndash;this is like a Shiny Input and Output.
My two cents is that Shiny should be introduced sooner rather than later for those beginning to learn R.The basis for my assertion is this that learning Shiny helped me conceptualize how make my own functions and added to my computer literacy regarding web development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I love most about Markdown</title>
      <link>/2018/01/19/what-i-love-most-about-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/19/what-i-love-most-about-markdown/</guid>
      <description>What I love most about Rmarkdown documents is writing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framework for Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>/2018/01/13/troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/13/troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>I transitioned from using databases to the RDS format to store evolving data. I ran into some trouble with the RDS format. I was stumped when previous working code would not work on a new data set.
My troubleshooting framework is as follows:
1) Look for silly typos.
2) Check your data types.
3) Isolate the issue.
The str function is the MVP of this troubleshooting adventure with a a little help from isolating the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go for a spin?</title>
      <link>/2018/01/11/go-for-a-spin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/11/go-for-a-spin/</guid>
      <description>One reason, I love Rmarkdown is that you can show and check your work. The benefits of rep
2+2  ## [1] 4 My Rmarkdown documents reports were long and somewhat intense. Last summer in R-studo community I came across this thread on how to organize a project. What struck me was the sourcing of scripts to generate Rmarkdown reports. Initially, I had a hard time with this because I could not figure out the working directory [see this post]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go for a spin?</title>
      <link>/2018/01/11/go-for-a-spin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/11/go-for-a-spin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notebooks with R</title>
      <link>/2018/01/05/notebooks-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/05/notebooks-with-r/</guid>
      <description>I have been ambivalent about using the notebook feature in R studio. I test drove Jupyter Notebooks, and I did not love the experience&amp;ndash;even using R.
However, I have slowly been adopting notebooks into my work flow and here are my use cases for notebooks.
One benefit is testing code or troubleshooting code, I am using in a shiny application.
A second benefit, I have noted with notebooks is that when Preview is selected; the html document will generate and includes the normal output but will also show code that does not work along with the error messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have an opinion</title>
      <link>/2017/12/10/have-an-opinion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/10/have-an-opinion/</guid>
      <description>Seth&amp;rsquo;s blog post today: I am proud that I practice this and promote this philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meditation</title>
      <link>/2017/12/10/meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/10/meditation/</guid>
      <description>I started the practice of meditating about 2 months ago. I am proud of myself for sticking to it. Some days are better than others but the key is learning that the rep or value is learning to recognize your thoughts have drifted and to come back.
Meditation is not a cure all but it does help you get out of a bad mental state quicker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balance</title>
      <link>/2017/12/08/balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/08/balance/</guid>
      <description>I recall walking into a college orientation and being uncertain if I was in the right room. The reason I was uncertain is because there were more parents in the room than college kids. It never occurred to me to take my parents with me to college orientation. My bias has been that those students who brought their parents with them were doomed to failure. I suspect my bias is wrong&amp;ndash;maybe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday night music</title>
      <link>/2017/12/08/friday-night-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/08/friday-night-music/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooper&#39;s Pace</title>
      <link>/2017/12/07/cooper-s-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/07/cooper-s-pace/</guid>
      <description>Attended a parent teacher conference this morning. I asked the teacher about the pace of his work and she said it&amp;rsquo;s at Cooper&amp;rsquo;s pace. This means that he is delibrate in his work; it took me nearly 40 years to work at a deliberate pace. did this change</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This needs a script</title>
      <link>/2017/12/06/automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/06/automation/</guid>
      <description>I was writing this morning about the benefits of automation and that even the most simple script is a method of automation. Ironically enough I finished parsing through a spreadsheet in preparation of a meeting and when I finished making copies; a new report was sent to me. This needs a script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diminishing Returns</title>
      <link>/2017/12/05/diminishing-returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/05/diminishing-returns/</guid>
      <description>I listened to a bunch of podcast today but I hardly recall any points. Ok, maybe one point stuck out and that is the value of being bored&amp;ndash;that means maybe not listening to so many podcast in short time frame. Today, the points really had no chance to stick.
This reminds to revisit the exercise of a working meditation while commuting to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>/2017/12/04/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/04/writing/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I had a couple of hints from blog posts/podcasts that I should be writing every day. Mostly their work/art prompts makes me want to write more.
I have been impressed with this blog by Austin Kleon and apparently everyone has known about Wait but why
I am determined not to code or write at night as I believe strong that impacts my sleep. I have been effective in getting up every morning writing code for an ongoing project and do not want to give that time up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bit of a hack</title>
      <link>/2017/12/02/a-bit-of-a-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/02/a-bit-of-a-hack/</guid>
      <description>This week I also finished up a feature of an application that I have been thinking about implementing. I wanted to summarize data entry by site location. The problem is that variable I am trying to summarize is free data entry&amp;ndash;hence many ways to write the name of the school and misspelling. I used a bit of hack with the gsub function.
My approach was this.
site$school &amp;lt;- toupper(site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;DOWDELL MIDDLE&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DOWDELL&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;DOWDELL MAGNET&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DOWDELL&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;DOWDELL SCHOOL&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DOWDELL&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;DOWDELLMIDDLE&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DOWDELL&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;DOWDELL MIDDLE&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DOWDELL&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;BLAKE ACADMY&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;BLAKE ACADEMY&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;BLAKEACADMY&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;BLAKE ACADEMY&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;BLAKE ACAMAY&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;BLAKE ACADEMY&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;DREAM ACADENY&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DREAM ACADEMY&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;FREEDOM MS&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;FREEDOM MIDDLE SCHOOL&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school) site$school &amp;lt;- gsub(&amp;quot;RIBUALT MDDLE&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;RIBAULT MIDDLE&amp;quot;, fixed=TRUE, site$school)  However, my sense is that there is a better way implement this with regular expressions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Entry Application</title>
      <link>/2017/12/01/data-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/01/data-management/</guid>
      <description>My intent was to build a data entry application with Python using the flask web environment. Somehow I managed to talk myself into using Shiny with the help of this post from Dean Atalli. It only took me about a couple of distracted hours with 3 kids to get through the tutorial and a morning to update a line of code to get the example working.
The pros to this approach are the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metallica Concerts with the Tidyverse</title>
      <link>/2017/11/19/metallica-concerts-with-the-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/19/metallica-concerts-with-the-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Most of my work in R is hidden from public view&amp;ndash;this seems like a blessing but is a curse in many respects; I get no feedback on my work in R.
I felt challenged and inspired by David Robinson&amp;rsquo;s post Advice to aspiring data scientist: start a blog
I completed the following analysis while in the midst of Hurricane Irma in September 2017, and I noticed the analysis utilizes many tidyverse functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Gaps</title>
      <link>/2017/11/15/more-gaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/15/more-gaps/</guid>
      <description>Writing this blog post on Gaps inspired me to re-read parts of the The Fifth Discipline by Peter Senge.
Gaps are a source of energy and Senge writes creative tension emerges when there is a gap between a person&amp;rsquo;s vision and reality. He uses a rubber band to illustrate that between vision and current reality is tension and the only way to break the tension is move reality toward the vision or move the vision toward reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test</title>
      <link>/2017/11/15/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/15/test/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaps</title>
      <link>/2017/11/08/gaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/08/gaps/</guid>
      <description>I keep coming across the concept of gaps&amp;ndash;more specifically the gap between reality and one&amp;rsquo;s vision for how reality should be. I first came across this concept in the Fifth Discipline by Peter Senge.
Currently I am reading Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning by Viktor Frankl.
This concept also came up in this interview of Ray Dalio that I listened to this week.
Frankl argues that mental health requires tension and the essence of being a human being is to close the gap between what is and what should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>working directory</title>
      <link>/2017/11/04/working-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/04/working-directory/</guid>
      <description>This seems basic in retrospect but one of the biggest challenges starting with R was understanding the concept of the working directory. For the most part, I figured the working directory out. However a bad habit that festered was changing the working directory in the chunks of my Rmd files.
Below is how I would configure my R chunks to read data or source scripts/functions. My data sits in multiple folders in the Project Folder, and I could not get the chunk to read the data or source scripts without setting the working directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/2017/10/31/ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/31/ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>I finally did it. I bought a refrubished laptop and installed Ubuntu to run R. The only trouble I had was installing R studio. It appears there are some challenges adding outside software on this platform&amp;ndash;Ubuntu 16.4
This article helped me throught the process Install R, R-Studio on Ubuntu
The only adjustment I had to make was to change the verison number of R-Studio I was downloading. Basically you update the version number; in my case instead of downloading 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviewing Functions</title>
      <link>/2017/10/14/reviewing-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/14/reviewing-functions/</guid>
      <description>I am starting on the new year of project and was revisiting some functions. I had a function that created a csv file of duplicate values for every organization that submitted data. The function was useful but a pain to run the function for every organization on separate chunks.
I figured there had to be better way. The following is an incremental improvement to the old process but I do have a sense there is a better way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduled Time</title>
      <link>/2017/10/14/scheduled-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/14/scheduled-time/</guid>
      <description>More on the book Deep Work. Cal Newport suggest scheduling every minute of your day.
This is challenging&amp;ndash;it takes training and practice but it has had profound impact on my productivity and well being.
Everyone has a plan &#39;til they are punched in the mouth.--Mike Tyson  Tasks either take longer or get completed quicker than expected thus there is a lot of adjustment to the schedule but it is well worth the effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where have you been my whole R Life</title>
      <link>/2017/09/30/where-have-you-been-my-whole-r-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/30/where-have-you-been-my-whole-r-life/</guid>
      <description>I hav been using the mutate function in dplyr for about a year now. However, I recently disovered a useful partner in the if_else function.
Ultimately, this is having a big impact on my workflow.
Below is my previous workflow. I would make seperate data frames and then bind the data frames together to run counts on the variables of interests.
lang_success_s &amp;lt;- langarts %&amp;gt;% filter(final &amp;gt;=2, pt_diff &amp;gt;=0)%&amp;gt;% #segment students with a final grade of C or higher and either maintained or increased their grade) mutate(&amp;quot;Success&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;TRUE&amp;quot;) #add variable Success dim(lang_success_s) lang_success_n &amp;lt;- langarts %&amp;gt;% filter(final &amp;gt;=2, pt_diff &amp;lt; 0) %&amp;gt;% #segment students with final Grade C or higher but decreased their grade mutate(&amp;quot;Success&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;FALSE&amp;quot;) # add variable Succes and fill in with false.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converging to Deep Work</title>
      <link>/2017/09/04/converging-to-deep-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/04/converging-to-deep-work/</guid>
      <description>I finished reading Deep Work by Cal Newport last month. Mr. Newport puts a framework and rules to what I think we already suspect. The book made me think of two other books Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maitenance and The War of Art. Both of these books put an emphasis on the benefits of craftmanship.
The concept of taking a break from focus rather than distraction is profound and his challenge to quit social media for 30 days benefical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging</title>
      <link>/2017/09/02/debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/02/debugging/</guid>
      <description> An approach to debugging Take the approach that most likely it is your fault that something is not working. You are simply not providing clear enough directions to the computer&amp;ndash;Your computer is simple and has no grit to problem solve your sloppiness.
Be thankful that that the computer is throwing an error rather giving a result that is wrong.
My approach to debugging accounts for the following:
 Data Types Spaces Syntax Errors and missing commas Updated package/library Other silly mistakes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership Development</title>
      <link>/2017/06/23/leadership-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/23/leadership-development/</guid>
      <description>Seth Godin published a blog post entititled &amp;ldquo;Is Judgement Involved?&amp;rdquo;. Seth&amp;rsquo;s point is the best jobs involve making decisions and taking responsbility&amp;ndash;hence risk.
I hope you disucss and share this idea; it&amp;rsquo;s still too much of a secret.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonprofits and Data Management</title>
      <link>/2017/06/11/nonprofits-and-data-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/11/nonprofits-and-data-management/</guid>
      <description>Do you agree that good infrastructure makes your life easier? Have you thought about the infrastructure of managing your program data? What are your systems that are in place to collect, manage and analyze your data?
My experience is that nonprofit organizations do not manage their program data in an optimal way and often manage their data in ways that make it challenging for employees to do their work. My gravest concern is that many nonprofit managers may not even recognize there is a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craftsmanship</title>
      <link>/2017/06/03/craftsmanship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/03/craftsmanship/</guid>
      <description>I have been thinking a lot about craftsmanship and trying to improve my work habits. I listened to a podcast that featured Vince Vaugn, and I was impressed with Vaughn&amp;rsquo;s story. Vaughn&amp;rsquo;s commitment to the craft of acting came through in the episode. In most cases, we rarely think about the process or the journey people take on their road to success. One aspect that stuck out what his commitment to the process and working to get better at acting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogdown lessons</title>
      <link>/2017/05/20/blogdown-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/20/blogdown-lessons/</guid>
      <description>One big challenge in rendering the site was using the R studio GUI Git. How many times did I restart my computer before I deduced the problem? The Git process would stall out.
To solve, I used the new Git desktop feature (https://desktop.github.com/) and it worked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fix for Disqus and Images</title>
      <link>/2017/01/12/images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/12/images/</guid>
      <description>Is the cure worse than the disease is what I pondered after I fixed an issue with Disqus comments.
I could not figure out how to get the Disqus Comment section to render on this site.
The fix for addressing the Disqus issues was changing the baseurl parameter from &amp;ldquo;/&amp;rdquo; to the name of the website in the confg.toml file. This Github Issue helped me resolve.
Before
baseurl= &amp;quot;/&amp;quot;  The fix</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Plain Markdown Post</title>
      <link>/2016/12/30/a-plain-markdown-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/30/a-plain-markdown-post/</guid>
      <description>This is a post written in plain Markdown (*.md) instead of R Markdown (*.Rmd). The major differences are:
 You cannot run any R code in a plain Markdown document, whereas in an R Markdown document, you can embed R code chunks (```{r}); A plain Markdown post is rendered through Blackfriday, and an R Markdown document is compiled by rmarkdown and Pandoc.  There are many differences in syntax between Blackfriday&amp;rsquo;s Markdown and Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workflow</title>
      <link>/2016/11/26/workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/26/workflow/</guid>
      <description>I have managed nonprofit evaluation projects with Github, Trello, Slack and WorkFlowy. Github and Trello are more for Task managment and there is some redundancy to the process but I make every attempt to integrate these tools.
What I think gets lost with Github, Trello, and Slack is that it is hard to see the entire picture. Workflowy is a narrative of what is going on with a project. The best part is being able to hide and then easily bring back content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hacked automation</title>
      <link>/2016/11/05/hacked-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/05/hacked-automation/</guid>
      <description>rmarkdown::render(“file.name”)
The line of code above has dramatically improved my workflow. The render function helped me reach the goal of creating an automated system of creating a status report and share data in a more efficient manner.
Ultimately, I still want to use the makefile feature but this process has helped identify the structure.
Here is a snippet of how the automation works
Created an Rmd file that does the following</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>makefiles and automation</title>
      <link>/2016/10/20/makefiles-and-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/20/makefiles-and-automation/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on trying to automate my workflow and want to learn to utilzie a makefile system to run a status report. To be honest, I am struggling to understand what I am reading from the tutorials.
Next step will be to clone the repository and work through the examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Kevin Gilds, MPA The title of this blog is R for the rest of us. The phrase R has a steep learning curve is true, and I hope to assist anyone leap up to R from spreadsheets.
Learning R and basic data science has helped me wrangle nonprofit program data and develop methods to make data processing and reporting easier. I came to R from a unique path&amp;ndash;the social service sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lorem Ipsum</title>
      <link>/2015/01/01/lorem-ipsum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 13:09:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/01/lorem-ipsum/</guid>
      <description>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects       code{white-space: pre;} pre:not([class]) { background-color: white; }  if (window.hljs &amp;&amp; document.readyState &amp;&amp; document.readyState === &#34;complete&#34;) { window.setTimeout(function() { hljs.initHighlighting(); }, 0); }  h1 { font-size: 34px; } h1.title { font-size: 38px; } h2 { font-size: 30px; } h3 { font-size: 24px; } h4 { font-size: 18px; } h5 { font-size: 16px; } h6 { font-size: 12px; } .table th:not([align]) { text-align: left; }    .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>About       code{white-space: pre;} pre:not([class]) { background-color: white; }  if (window.hljs &amp;&amp; document.readyState &amp;&amp; document.readyState === &#34;complete&#34;) { window.setTimeout(function() { hljs.initHighlighting(); }, 0); }  h1 { font-size: 34px; } h1.title { font-size: 38px; } h2 { font-size: 30px; } h3 { font-size: 24px; } h4 { font-size: 18px; } h5 { font-size: 16px; } h6 { font-size: 12px; } .table th:not([align]) { text-align: left; }    .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>Test Driving readxl Kevin
2018-02-23
Introduction I am interested in school attendance data and found an interesting data set on the Florida Department of Education Website. This seemed like a good time to learn the r readxl package in order to wrangle spreadsheets in the wild. This post closely follows closely with theexamples on the Github Repo.
The file consists of data from a survey of schools in Florida that provides a count of students who were absent more than 21 days in the school year 2015-2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>Test Driving readxl package Kevin
2018-02-26
Introduction I am interested in school attendance data and found an interesting data set on the Florida Department of Education Website. This seemed like a good time to learn the r readxl package in order to wrangle spreadsheets in the wild. This post closely follows closely with theexamples on the Github Repo.
The file consists of data from a survey of schools in Florida that provides a count of students who were absent more than 21 days in the school year 2015-2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KEVIN W. GILDS, MPA</title>
      <link>/kevins_resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kevins_resume/</guid>
      <description>Cell: 863-399-4363 email: kevingilds@gmail.com Lakeland, FL      Skill Summary   Excel/Access Calculate/Interpret Statistics R Programming Git/Github SQL       Work Experience PROJECT MANAGMENT
 Led team in managing the process of helping seniors obtain eligibility for Long Term Care Services: assigned workloads, set milestones, and monitored progress of monthly releases, resulting in achieving performance measures every month over 2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KEVIN W. GILDS, MPA</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Cell: 863-399-4363 email: kevingilds@gmail.com Lakeland, FL      Skill Summary   Excel/Access Calculate/Interpret Statistics R Programming Git/Github SQL       Work Experience DATA SCIENCE
 Created functions, scripts and reports in R to manage survey and academic data for the Get REAL! statewide mentoring program: resulting in a work process that is automated and reproducible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Featured Posts Metallica Concerts with the Tidy Verse
Shiny Applications Florida Education Absences Application</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hacked automation</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/hacked-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/hacked-automation/</guid>
      <description>rmarkdown::render(&amp;ldquo;file.name&amp;rdquo;)
The line of code above has dramatically improved my workflow. The render function helped me reach the goal of creating an automated system of creating a status report and share data in a more efficient manner.
Ultimately, I still want to use the makefile feature but this process has helped identify the structure.
Here is a snippet of how the automation works
Created an Rmd file that does the following</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>