<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogdown on R for the rest of us</title>
    <link>/categories/blogdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogdown on R for the rest of us</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/blogdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Note to self</title>
      <link>/2018/05/12/note-to-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/12/note-to-self/</guid>
      <description>My post from yesterday included images of both side of an index card. Apparently, I need the practice of adding images to my posts. I tend to forget to committ the files to the static folder and get stumpeed for about 10 minutes on why the image does not render online.
Hence a good is excuse to render this gif file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post vs Projects</title>
      <link>/2018/05/09/post-vs-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/09/post-vs-projects/</guid>
      <description>I just completed a draft of a post; I am not completely statisfied with the rendered output for a host of reasons. My current theme has a left side-bar and for this piece I think the sidebar inhibits the conent&amp;ndash;I suspect the content would look better with an entire page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogdown lessons</title>
      <link>/2017/05/20/blogdown-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/20/blogdown-lessons/</guid>
      <description>One big challenge in rendering the site was using the R studio GUI Git. How many times did I restart my computer before I deduced the problem? The Git process would stall out.
To solve, I used the new Git desktop feature (https://desktop.github.com/) and it worked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fix for Disqus and Images</title>
      <link>/2017/01/12/images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/12/images/</guid>
      <description>Is the cure worse than the disease is what I pondered after I fixed an issue with Disqus comments.
I could not figure out how to get the Disqus Comment section to render on this site.
The fix for addressing the Disqus issues was changing the baseurl parameter from &amp;ldquo;/&amp;rdquo; to the name of the website in the confg.toml file. This Github Issue helped me resolve.
Before
baseurl= &amp;quot;/&amp;quot;  The fix</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>