<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shiny on R for the rest of us</title>
    <link>/tags/shiny/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shiny on R for the rest of us</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/shiny/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>shiny-dashboard</title>
      <link>/2018/06/12/shiny-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/12/shiny-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>This morning, I worked on laying the infrastructure for adding a match indicator in my Shiny app dashboard. I also updated the match script to send the rds file to the bookdown directory.
My next step is update the server section to render the match information. It may worth considering changing the layout of my table.
 worktime 50 minutes
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freeing Educational Data With A Shiny App</title>
      <link>/2018/04/04/freeing-educational-data-with-a-shiny-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/04/freeing-educational-data-with-a-shiny-app/</guid>
      <description>I built a Shiny Application to free data from a spreadsheet on the Florida Department of Education website. I learned a lot&amp;ndash;specifically making the input variable reactive, sprinkling in html to make it look how I want, and using the DT package for useful rendering of the data.
Reactive I knew that I wanted to split the data into school types&amp;ndash;elementary, middle, and high and had a sense that my input value would need to be reactive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Shiny</title>
      <link>/2018/01/19/shiny-for-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/19/shiny-for-teaching/</guid>
      <description>It was a struggle for me to learn to write my own functions in R. The moment it did sink in; My though was this&amp;ndash;this is like a Shiny Input and Output.
My two cents is that Shiny should be introduced sooner rather than later for those beginning to learn R.The basis for my assertion is this that learning Shiny helped me conceptualize how make my own functions and added to my computer literacy regarding web development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>