<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Management on R for the rest of us</title>
    <link>/categories/data-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Management on R for the rest of us</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/data-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The point</title>
      <link>/2018/06/01/the-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/01/the-point/</guid>
      <description>I came across this article on twitter tonight.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know that I have the expertise to concur or disagree with this article&amp;ndash;I mean the premise is correct being able to solve business problems seems like a &amp;lsquo;no-brainer&amp;rsquo;.
Another important skill is political skills. Sometimes you see what others do not see and you have to sell the vision to the right people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rain, Excel &amp; a CSV File</title>
      <link>/2018/05/15/csv-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/15/csv-files/</guid>
      <description>Monday was a rainy day and a perfect day to keep wiping out a database table. Whenever, I uploaded a CSV file it wiped out a database table. I only managed to do it twice.
 I learned Excel removes blank columns in CSV files when saved
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonprofits and Data Management</title>
      <link>/2017/06/11/nonprofits-and-data-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/11/nonprofits-and-data-management/</guid>
      <description>Do you agree that good infrastructure makes your life easier? Have you thought about the infrastructure of managing your program data? What are your systems that are in place to collect, manage and analyze your data?
My experience is that nonprofit organizations do not manage their program data in an optimal way and often manage their data in ways that make it challenging for employees to do their work. My gravest concern is that many nonprofit managers may not even recognize there is a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>